本字幕由 YYeTs人人影視 翻譯創作
歡迎愛好者加入我們  www.YYeTs.com
翻譯：cainvki  angevil wingstoflygrey  依戀Elaine  蟬衣夏影
校對：海因塈 監製：可樂嘻嘻  後期：yyp
你是誰
Who are you?
西班牙  加的斯  [西班牙港口城市]
怎麼回事
What is this?
陛下  我們用漁網撈起了他  漁網
Your Majesty, caught him up in a fishing net. A fishing net.
大人  他有許多故事  那些故事...
Sire, he's been telling stories. Stories that...
我們相信他找到了
We believe he's found a...
龐塞·德萊昂[西班牙探險家]
Ponce de Leon.
他說他找到了龐塞·德萊昂的船
Says he found Ponce de Leon's ship.
-還乘那船出海過  -不  我告訴過你
- Or sailed on it. - No, I told you,
龐塞·德萊昂死了兩百多年了
Ponce de Leon died 200 years ago.
沒錯  可他終其一生在尋找什麼吧
Aye, but he died searching for something, didn't he?
不老泉
The Fountain of Youth.
你何時能啟航
How soon can you sail?
潮起之時
With the tide.
看一看瞧一瞧  幸運草
Over here! Lucky heather!
英國  倫敦
都來買我的海盜佩劍
Pirate swords! Pirate swords!
今日處決海盜  快去看吶
Pirate's execution today. Watch him swing!
海盜玩偶
Pirate puppets!
接招吧  小子
Take that, you!
快點  爸爸  要不就趕不及看絞刑了
Hurry, Papa, or we'll miss the hanging!
那不是絞刑  寶貝  那是審判
It's not a hanging, dear, it's a trial.
下午才行刑呢
The hanging comes this afternoon.
今日處決海盜
Pirate hanging today!
快點  起來
Come on. Up you get.
快走  海盜
Move along, pirate.
是不是該叫你  "海盜船長"
Or should I say, "Captain Pirate"?
快點  快走
Come on. Come on! Up you go.
安靜  肅靜
Quiet! Order!
安靜
Quiet!
傳喚臭名昭著
Now appearing before the court,
聲名狼藉的海盜  劫掠者
the notorious and infamous pirate, pillager,
-匪徒  -安靜
- and highwayman... - Quiet!
傑克·史派羅船長上庭
...Captain Jack Sparrow!
我說過了  我叫吉布斯  約什米·吉布斯
I told you, the name's Gibbs! Joshamee Gibbs!
-我還要說多少...  -注意
- How many times... - Hear ye, hear ye!
全體起立  有請主持本次庭審
Presiding over these trials,
尊敬的史密斯法官大人
all rise and attend, the Right Honorable Justice Smith!
大人
My dear sir.
安靜
Quiet!
現在
Now...
是什麼情況
...what do we have here?
傑克
Jack?
閉嘴
Shut up!
我不認識他
I don't recognize him.
沒這必要  你剛說什麼
Not necessary. You were saying?
我不是傑克·史派羅
Jack Sparrow is not my name.
我是約什米·吉布斯
My name is Joshamee Gibbs.
是嗎
Is that so?
-上面寫著你是傑克·史派羅  -我說過了
- It says Jack Sparrow here. - I told 'em.
我不叫傑克·史派羅
I'm not Jack Sparrow,
但我很樂意向庭上指認他
who I would be happy to identify to the court
要是這能證明我的清白
if it would help my case.
我認為這辯護並不高明
I think that would be a poor defense,
除非你還想像頭蠢海豹一樣被打一下
unless you want to be bludgeoned again like a harp seal.
囚犯辯稱自己不是傑克·史派羅
The prisoner claims of being innocent
你們陪審團以為如何
to being Jack Sparrow. How do you find?
沒有庭審  可我們是來檢驗證據...
No trial? But aren't we here to examine the evidence...
團長  告訴我你的結論  有罪嗎
Foreman, your finding. Guilty?
有罪裁斷將處以絞刑
Guilty verdict means he'll hang.
吊死他  把他吊起來
Hang him! String him up!
-有罪吧  -這不公平
- Guilty? - That's not fair!
閉嘴
Shut it.
約什米·吉布斯  由於你並非傑克·史派羅
Joshamee Gibbs, the crime of which you've been found guilty of
所以你沒有犯下他的罪行
is being innocent of being Jack Sparrow.
因此本庭赦免你的死刑
I hereby commute your sentence,
宣判你將被處以徒刑
and order that you be imprisoned for the remainder
在監獄堳袡L你那行屍走肉般的悲慘餘生
of your miserable, moribund, mutton-chopped life.
-什麼  -吊死他
- What?! - Hang him!
-吊死他  -閉庭
- Hang him! - There.
-胡說八道  -吊死他  把他吊起來
- Balderdash! - String him up! Hang him high!
法庭將安排將囚犯押至
Means shall be arranged to transport this prisoner
倫敦塔
to the Tower of London.
非常感謝
Thanks very much.
拜拜
Ta.
快點  給我上去
Come on. Get up there.
上去
Get up!
真見鬼  這下咱們倆都得進去了
Hell's teeth. Now we're both headed for prison.
別擔心  我買通了車伕
Not to worry. I've paid off the driver.
用不了十分鐘  咱們就出了倫敦城  有馬等著
Ten minutes, we'll be outside London Town, horses waiting.
今晚  我們就能到海邊
Tonight, we make the coast.
再然後就是弄艘船的問題了
Then it's just a matter of finding a ship.
-這都計劃好了嗎  -沒錯
- All part of the plan, yes? - Exactly.
我今早剛到倫敦城
I arrived in London Town just this morning
來救和絞刑架有個約會的
to rescue one Joshamee
名叫約什米·吉布斯的傢伙
Gibbs from one appointment with the gallows.
鑒於你目前還活得好好的
Seeing as how you're still alive,
我認為目前為止還挺成功
I'd say it's all been very successful thus far.
你怎麼了  吉布斯
What happened to you, Gibbs?
我以為你出海了或是在忙別的
I thought you were employed elsewhere or otherwise engaged.
沒錯  可我一直在
Aye. But I always listened
打探黑珍珠號的消息
like a thief for news of the Black Pearl.
誰也不知道她會停靠在何處
Nobody's seen where she might next make port.
後來  我聽到流言
Then, I hear a rumor:
傑克·史派羅在倫敦找了條船  在招募水手
Jack Sparrow's in London with a ship and looking for a crew.
-才怪  -可我是這麼聽說
- Am not. - But that's what I heard.
說你今晚就在
Fact is, you're signing up men tonight.
"船長之女"酒吧招人
Pub called The Captain's Daughter.
-才怪  -我是覺得有點奇怪
- Am not! - Well, I thought it a bit odd,
不過話說回來  你做事總是這麼不靠譜
but then, you've never been the most predictable of sorts.
跟我好好說說
Tell me something.
這兒還有個叫傑克·史派羅的傢伙冒充我的大名
There is another Jack Sparrow out there sullying my good name?
-冒名的騙子  -沒錯
- An impostor. - Indeed.
不過  人家有船
But... an impostor with a ship.
還有水手
And in need of a crew.
這些  蒼天在上  我也會有
Which, as fate would have it, so am I.
你怎麼樣  傑克
What about you, Jack?
我上回聽說  你拼了老命要找那不老泉
Last I heard, you were hell-bent to find the Fountain of Youth.
運氣如何
Any luck?
經歷了千辛萬苦後  我頓悟了
Circumstances arose and forced a compelling insight
此行既需要勇氣  也得小心謹慎
regarding discretion and valor.
-那就是說  你放棄了  -我沒有
- Meaning, you gave up. - I did not.
我還是一樣不要命  妥妥的
I am just as bent as ever. Hellishly so.
我一定要嘗嘗那泉水  吉布斯水手長  我把話撂在這兒
I shall taste those waters, Master Gibbs. Mark my words.
真快
Short trip.
這也是計劃好的吧
All part of the plan, yes?
不是
No.
你就是傑克·史派羅嗎
You are Jack Sparrow?
你好像漏了"船長"二字
There should be a "Captain" In there somewhere.
我聽過你
I've heard of you.
你一定知道我是誰
And you know who I am.
看起來挺面熟  我是不是恐嚇過你
Face is familiar. Have I threatened you before?
在你面前的是喬治·奧古斯都
You are in the presence of George Augustus,
伯倫瑞克-呂納堡公爵
Duke of Brunswick-Luneburg,
神聖羅馬帝國的首要財務官和選帝侯
Archtreasurer and Prince-elector of the Holy Roman Empire,
大不列顛及愛爾蘭的國王  也是你的國王
King of Great Britain and Ireland, and of you.
-還是沒想起來  -我聽說
- Doesn't ring a bell. - I am informed
你來倫敦是為了招募水手
you have come to London to procure a crew for your ship.
惡毒的流言  假的
Vicious rumor. Not true.
那你就是在謊稱自己是傑克·史派羅
Then you lied to me when you told me you were Jack Sparrow.
我是傑克·史派羅  不過我來不是為了招水手
I am Jack Sparrow, but I'm not here to procure a crew.
那是...別人
That is... someone else.
別的叫傑克·史派羅的人
Someone else named Jack Sparrow.
你給我找錯了人
You've brought me the wrong wastrel.
給我找來本人  把這個冒牌貨處理掉
Find the proper one and dispose of this impostor.
不  等等  等會兒
No, wait, wait, wait. Hang on a minute.
我是傑克·史派羅  獨一無二的
I'm Jack Sparrow, the one and only.
我就在倫敦
And I am in London.
你要招募水手
To procure a crew.
進行一場偉大的航行
To undertake a voyage
-目標是那什麼泉...  -什麼
- to the Fountain... - What?
誰來解開那些見鬼的鎖鏈
Will someone please remove these infernal chains?
來來來
Come, come.
我們知道你有幅地圖
We know you're in possession of a map.
那就沒收那地圖  然後送他上絞架
So confiscate the map, and to the gallows with him!
你有地圖嗎
Have you a map?
-沒  -那在哪兒
- No. - Where is it?
說實話  我弄丟了
The truth? I lost it.
-實際上  就在前不久  -我收到消息
- Quite recently, in fact. - I have a report.
說西班牙人已知道了不老泉的所在
The Spanish have located the Fountain of Youth.
我可不能讓可憎的西班牙國王
I will not have some melancholy Spanish monarch,
一個天主教徒  獲得永生
a Catholic, gain eternal life!
你當真知道去不老泉的路
You do know the way to the Fountain?
當然  我可是傑克船長
Of course I do. Look at me.
你能領導我們的遠征隊
You could guide an expedition.
如果您允許  大大
With your permission, your heinie,
還提供一艘船
you will be providing, then, a ship...
和水手嗎
...and a crew?
還有船長
And a captain.
午安  陛下
Afternoon, sire.
恕我冒昧  為什麼沒把那傢伙銬起來
If I may be so bold, why is that man not in chains?
必須立即銬上他
He must be manacled at once.
在我這宮殿之中  沒這必要
At the center of my palace? Hardly.
赫克托
Hector.
看到海盜老友從良了真好
How nice to see a fellow pirate make good of himself.
海盜  不  是私掠船長
Pirate? Nay. Privateer.
為捍衛王上的權威
On a sanctioned mission under
而被賦予此項使命
the authority and protection of the Crown.
就算是吧  不過首先
As may be, but first,
我親愛的黑珍珠號哪去了
what has become of my beloved Pearl?
我失去了黑珍珠號  正如我這條腿
I lost the Pearl as I lost my leg.
-失去了什麼意思  -是的
- Lost the Pearl? - Aye.
我曾奮勇守護她  可她終不能免於沉沒
I defended her mightily enough, but she be sunk nonetheless.
船在人在  船亡人亡
If that ship be sunk properly, you should be sunk with it.
巴博薩船長  我們每耽擱一秒鐘
Captain Barbossa, each second we tarry,
西班牙人都會多甩開我們一點
the Spanish outdistance us.
我非常相信  以你的熱忱
I have every confidence you will prevail and be rewarded
你必將無往不勝  贏得我的獎賞
with the high station you so desire.
-願盡綿薄之力  陛下  -你也太不要臉了
- To serve doth suffice, sire. - You, sir, have stooped.
傑克  咱倆的日子還長著呢
Jack, our sands be all but run.
識時務  方能成俊傑
Where's the harm in joining the winning side?
而你面前的我確實更有地位了
And you do meet a nicer class of person.
這我都能理解
I understand everything.
除了你那假髮
Except that wig.
他要逃走了  抓住他
He's getting away! Stop him!
-攔住他  -不  攔住那個海盜
- Head him off! - No! Stop that pirate!
下來
Come down!
-他逃走了  -交給我吧  陛下
- He escaped? - Leave it to me, sire.
衛兵  衛兵
Guards! Guards!
-準備好武器  -遵命  大人
- Arms at ready! - Aye, sir!
找到他
Find him!
撿著就是我的
Finders keepers!
在那兒
There!
這就完事了
Is that it?
停下  攔下那輛馬車
Halt! Stop that carriage!
截住他
Head him off!
讓開
Out of the way!
抓住那個海盜
Stop that pirate!
都讓開
Move out of the way!
抓住那個人
Stop that man!
別讓他跑了
Don't let him get away!
開火
Fire!
他跑了  追上他  抓住他
He's getting away! After him! Stop him!
追上他
After him!
下賤的海盜
Filthy pirate.
你好  小傑
Hello, Jackie.
你好  老爸
Hello, Dad.
我聽說你在招募水手
I heard you're putting together a crew.
流言傳了一千遍  也就成了真
If enough people keep saying it, it must be true.
我知道你要去哪  不老泉
I heard where you're headed. The Fountain.
你去過嗎
Have you been there?
你看我這張臉  像是去過不老泉的樣子嗎
Does this face look like it's been to the Fountain of Youth?
-光線問題  -兒子  不老泉
- Depends on the light. - Son, the Fountain.
需要一些特殊道具完成儀式
There'll be items required for the profane ritual.
兩隻聖盃
Two chalices.
-地圖上是有個聖盃  -兩隻  銀製的
- On the map there was a chalice. - Two, silver.
在龐塞·德萊昂的船上  你需要兩隻
From the Ponce de Leon ship. You'll need both.
-為什麼  -完成儀式  別傻了  小傑
- For? - The ritual. Don't be a fool, Jackie.
做好完全的準備  再起航
Find out every detail before you set sail.
啟航  那很好
Oh, set sail. Love to.
可我得有艘船才行
But for that, I may need a ship.
那邊的那些傢伙  他們有船
Those folk, over there, they have a ship.
他們現在就在招水手
They're signing up sailors right now.
我的心被丘比特射中
My heart is pierced by Cupid
我對金子也不屑一顧
I disdain all glittering gold
最後一件事  小傑
And one last thing, Jackie.
不老泉會考驗你  記住我的話
The Fountain will test you. Mark my words.
我的心被丘比特射中
My heart is pierced by Cupid
我對金子也不屑一顧
I disdain all glittering gold
只有快樂勇敢的水手
There is nothing can console me
能讓我的心得到慰藉
But my jolly sailor bold
我聽說你們在招水手
I hear you be recruiting a crew.
是的
Aye. That is,
傑克·史派羅正在準備一場探險
Jack Sparrow be putting together a modest venture.
你有點神經兮兮的呀
You got some nerve, ain't ya?
穿成這副模樣
Turning up here dressed like that?
你算哪根蔥  冒名頂替的嗎
What are you, some kind of impostor?
你知道我是誰嗎  朋友
Have you any idea who I am, mate?
喂  哥兒幾個
Oi, muckers!
這兒有個哥們連自己是誰都想不起來
There's a bloke here what's forgotten his own name!
大夥兒  我要和史派羅一起出海了
Lads, I'm sailing with Sparrow.
誰來給水手買杯酒喝
Who'll buy a sailor a drink?
下一位
Who's next?
再來一點
Bring us some more of those ones.
對  再來四個
Yeah, make it four.
你偷了我的身份  我來要回我自己
You've stolen me, and I'm here to take meself back.
別學我
Stop doing that.
只有一個人會那招
Only one person alive knows that move.
早就想這麼幹了
Always wanted to do that.
你好  安琪莉卡
Hello, Angelica.
你好  傑克  沒想到吧
Hello, Jack. Are you impressed?
我想有那麼一兩次  我差點就能殺了你
I think I almost killed you once or twice there.
你這真摯的讚揚讓我分外感動
I'm touched at this most sincerest form of flattery.
可這是為什麼
But why?
你是唯一一個我能裝得像的海盜
You were the only pirate I thought I would pass for.
這可不是什麼好話
That is not a compliment.
別擔心  傑克  我早就原諒你了
Don't worry, Jack. I forgave you a long time ago.
-原諒什麼  我甩了你  -好好想想  是我甩的你
- For what? For leaving you? - Recall that I left you.
紳士總得縱容女士沉溺在她的小幻想中
A gentleman allows a lady to maintain her fictions.
聽著  史派羅  只要我的水手有錢可賺
Look, Sparrow. As long as my sailors get their money,
不管是什麼樣的事情  他們都能湊合
they're willing to put up with any number of peculiarities.
有那麼一件事情  我可湊合不了
There is one peculiarity with which I will not put up with.
我來演船長  必須這樣
I will be impersonated as "Captain." Nothing less.
要想當船長  你得先有艘船
Well, for that, you need a ship,
而我  恰恰就有一艘
and as it turns out, I have one.
我正好需要一艘船
I could use a ship.
我聽說你去過那
I hear tell you've been to the Fountain.
最近小道消息真不少
There be a lot of hear-telling going on these days.
-不老泉  -親愛的安琪莉卡  別擔心
- The Fountain of Youth.  - Dearest Angelica, fret not.
你還年輕
You still have a few usable years left.
真會講話
Always so charming.
你沒回答我
You didn't answer me.
哦對  至於不老泉  那是浪費時間  真的...
Aye. Regarding the Fountain. Waste of time, really...
夫人  發現一群可疑的人
Milady, I see unseamanlike
不像船員  像是來找茬兒的
fellows of an officious-looking nature.
無恥的海盜  抓住他們  這幫無賴
Wretched pirates! Find 'em! Maggots!
你的朋友嗎
Friends of yours?
我可能不小心惹火了國王之類的人
I may have unintentionally slighted some king or other.
打開
Open it!
-你還是沒變  -能給點提示嗎
- Yeah, you haven't changed.  - Implying the need?
那好
Yes.
打開門  這是國王的命令
Open this door, in the name of His Majesty.
你背叛了我  還引誘和利用我
You betrayed me. You seduced me and you used me.
騙術什麼的我本來並不擅長
I was innocent of the ways of men.
就一個我要帶壞的人來說
You demonstrated a lot of
你有點過於強大了
technique for someone I supposedly corrupted.
太危險了  快點  夫人
Imminent danger. Here, now, milady!
打開
Open it!
我正要宣誓  你卻...
I was ready to take my vows. And you...
你究竟怎麼會出現在西班牙的女修道院
What were you doing in a Spanish convent, anyway?
把那當妓院了  純屬失誤
Mistook it for a brothel. Honest mistake.
-他在那  -那邊
- There he is!  - Over there!
我們的處境很被動
We are at a disadvantage.
那是你  我可不像某人裝成別人
Speak for yourself. Unlike some who pretend to be,
實際上連人家一根毛都及不上
but cannot, in fact, hold a candle to,
我才是傑克·史派羅船長
I am Captain Jack Sparrow.
你怎麼能說我利用你
How can you say I used you?
你明明知道
You know exactly how.
我知道  但你怎麼能說出口
I know, but how can you say it?
-那到底是什麼  -什麼是什麼
- So, what is it?  - What is what?
不老泉
About the Fountain.
你知道什麼
What do you know?
龐塞·德萊昂的兩個聖盃
You don't happen to be in possession
不會就剛好在你這吧
of two silver chalices, circa Ponce de Leon?
-沒有  -我想也是
- No.  - Thought not.
-怎麼  -我聽到有些說法
- Why?  - I hear stories.
傳言
Rumors.
你肯定知道儀式吧
You are, of course, aware of the ritual.
是的
Yes, I am.
是什麼樣的  需要什麼道具
What is it? What is required?
一條美人魚  傑克
A mermaid, Jack.
一定是搞錯了
There's been a mistake.
我是被判無期徒刑  不是死刑
It's a life sentence, not death. Life!
-巴博薩  -謝謝  先生們
- Barbossa.  - Thank you, gentlemen.
我相信你會繫繩索
I trust you can tie a noose.
這是強人所難
That's a hard thing,
讓人給自己綁絞繩
forcing a man to twist his own hanging rope.
這叫自作自受
You must lie in your bed the way you made it.
你們倆怎麼了
What's happened to you?
-傑克·史派羅呢  -他跑了
- Where be Jack Sparrow?  - He escaped.
我很趕時間  吉布斯
I'm on a tight schedule, Gibbs.
皇家海軍明晨就要出發
The HMS Providence sets sail at first light.
如果你不想死後滿嘴蒼蠅
If you do not care to watch it hanging here dead,
還被掛在這堨亄
with a mouth full of flies...
就趕快招了
...speak now.
帶上我  羅盤上的所有地點...
Take me with you. Any point of the compass...
帶你去哪  吉布斯  不老泉嗎
Take you where, Gibbs? The Fountain? Aye?
傑克也要去那兒嗎
Is that where Jack be headed?
你能給我什麼  吉布斯
Have you anything you can offer me, Gibbs?
有嗎
Anything at all?
說白了  你見不到黎明了
Upon me naked word, you'll not see the dawn.
把它給我
Hand it over.
-你個蠢貨  -我有足夠時間
- You fool!  - I had just enough time
好好研究了下那張地圖
to study those infernal circles.
所有路線和目的地  全都牢牢記在這了
Every route, every destination. All safe... in here.
歡迎回到皇家海軍  吉布斯水手長
Welcome back to His Majesty's navy, Master Gibbs.
起床  水手
Show a leg, sailor!
遵命  長官
Aye, sir.
啥
What?
-這是個天大的誤會  -繼續走
- There's been a horrible mistake.  - Keep moving.
-我不該在這  -許多人在海上醒來
- I'm not supposed to be here.  - Many a man's woken up at sea,
大腦一片空白
no idea what, when, wherefore or why.
完全不記得前天晚上是在哪簽的協議
No memory of the night afore, whence he signed up
又是在哪把佣金全部買了酒喝
and drank away all his bonus money.
不  不  不  你不明白  夥計
No, no, no. You don't understand, mate.
我是傑克·史派羅船長  如假包換  獨一無二
I'm Captain Jack Sparrow. The original. The only.
我叫史考姆  很高興認識你  好了  走吧
Scrum, and the pleasure's all mine. Now, keep moving.
史考姆
Scrum.
過來
Get your elbows in!
這怎麼有一口玻璃棺材
Why is there a glass coffin?
我看起來像是管事兒的嗎
Do I look like a man in charge?
-這是哪兒  -不好意思  史派羅船長
- Where am I?   - 'Scuse me, Captain Sparrow, sir.
我很榮幸地歡迎您登上這艘
I be right honored to welcome you aboard
臭名昭著的安娜王后復仇號
our world-renowned vessel of infamy, Queen Anne's Revenge.
黑鬍子
Blackbeard.
幹活兒
Work!
-這人挺古怪  -他是還魂屍
- He's a curious one.  - He's been zombiefied.
加勒比海一些部族的宗教信仰  被巫術驅動的死屍
還魂屍
Zombiefied.
黑鬍子干的  管事兒的都是
Blackbeard's doing. All the officers are the same.
這樣的人更服從命令
Makes 'em more compliant.
還有沒完沒了的壞脾氣
And perpetually ill-tempered.
-快擦  -好
- Come on. Scrub.  - Yeah.
拉  拉  拉
Pull! Pull! Pull!
我們航行了至少五天
Five days underway, at least.
是啊  你是根據海的味道辨別的嗎
Aye. You can tell that by the smell of the sea?
船員的味道
Smell of the crew.
那個可憐鬼做了什麼
Oi. What did that poor sod do?
我怎麼保證不重蹈覆轍
And how can I make sure to not?
他嗎  是個牧師
Him? Churchly fellow.
總是宣揚上帝萬能
Always going on about the Lord Almighty.
船上還有講《聖經》的牧師
Bible-thumper on this ship?
用他的話說是傳教士
A missionary is his story.
我聽說他在一次突襲中被逮住
What I heard was he got captured in a raid.
船上其他人都死了  除了他
Rest of the ship got killed, but not 'im.
因為他的虔誠信仰
First mate wouldn't let it happen
大副放過了他
on account of his premier standing with the Lord.
大副她為了這人冒了很大風險
A first mate sticking her neck out for some prisoner.
你能想到嗎
That you don't see.
她?  大副是女的?
"Her"? First mate is a "Her"?
回去幹活兒
Back to work!
船速很穩定
Steady as she goes.
你個殘忍  沒良心  遭報應的卑鄙小人
You are a ruthless, soulless, cross-grained cur.
-我跟你說過我有條船  -不對  是黑鬍子的船
- I told you I had a ship.  - No, Blackbeard has a ship,
而我就被囚禁在這條船上
upon which I am now imprisoned.
我們可以聯手  傑克
We can do this, Jack.
不老泉  你一直都想去
The Fountain of Youth, like you always wanted.
黑鬍子  愛德華·提奇  所有海盜都懼怕的海盜
Blackbeard. Edward Teach. The pirate all pirates fear.
沒事兒喜歡給屍體還魂
Resurrector of the dead in his spare time.
-他會聽我的話  -他不聽任何人
- He will listen to me.  - He listens to no one.
連他女兒也不聽嗎
Maybe to his own daughter?
女兒  親生的嗎
Daughter as in... beget by?
多年失散  最近團聚
Long-lost. Recently found.
她全心全意愛著她的父親
Who loves her dear papa with all her soul.
-他居然信了  -憑我的三寸不爛之舌
- He bought that?  - I sold that.
那麼想去不老泉的是他
Then it's the Fountain of Youth for him,
或者你和他  但不是你和我
or him and you, not you and me.
錯了  傑克  最妙的來了
No, Jack, that's the best part.
他會死
He will be dead.
那你就能獨吞了
You'll be handling that part yourself, then?
有個預言
There is a prophecy.
或許你不相信神奇力量
Maybe you don't believe in the supernatural.
不  不  不  我也見過幾次
Oh, no, no. I've seen a thing or two.
預言就是
The prophecy is this:
黑鬍子在兩星期內
Blackbeard will meet his death within a fortnight
會死於一個獨腿男人手中
at the hands of a one-legged man.
所以他要找不老泉  傑克
That's why he needs the Fountain, Jack.
吉布斯水手長  我們少張海圖
Master Gibbs, short we are a map.
或許你該給我們指個方向
Perhaps you'd be so kind as to provide us an heading.
你能行行好  給我來點酒嗎
Be a gem and pour me a gulper.
不  我們不是海盜  這是條私掠船  吉布斯水手長
Nay. We be privateers, not pirates, Master Gibbs.
看在國王的名義上  我們就得這樣
And in the king's name, we behave as such.
是  船長
Aye, Captain.
我們的航線對嗎  吉布斯
Be we on the proper course, Gibbs?
沒錯  不信看那邊
Aye, it be proper. There's your proof.
西班牙人
The Spaniard.
全體船員  到戰鬥崗位  到上風向
All hands! Battle stations! Get to windward!
-全體船員  上風向  -帆向上拉緊兩個點
- All hands, windward!  - Harden up two points!
-兩個點  -解開炮索
- Two points!  - Cast loose the cannons!
-炮手就位  -就位  炮手準備完畢 船長
- Gunners, take posts!  - Take position! Gunners ready, sir!
-準備發射  -待命
- Out! Thrust!  - Await orders.
穩住
Steady!
大炮準備完畢  等待指示  船長
Guns armed, awaiting orders, sir.
船長  下命令嗎  船長
Sir. Orders, sir?
他根本沒在意我們
He never so much as turned his head.
不老泉才是目標
The Fountain is the prize.
看來他們不屑於襲擊我們
It appears we be not even worth the time it'd take to sink us.
現在我們落後了  全員  快速前進
And now we've fallen behind. All hands, make more sail!
全員  加速前進
All hands, more sail!
加速前進  迎著風浪向前
Ride hard between wind and tide!
先生們  我們的話題是  奪權
The topic, gentlemen, is mutiny.
叛亂
Mutiny most foul.
沒錯  我是要為傑克·史派羅效力  不是什麼冒牌貨
Aye. I signed up to sail under Jack Sparrow, not some pretender.
更何況還是個女人
And a lady, at that.
還不知道船上都是些可怕的神奇生物
And mention was failed to be made of this uncanny crew.
他們弄彎了我的腳趾
Make my toes curl, they do.
所有的我都弄來了
I got 'em. All of them.
-幹得好  -好小子
- Well done.  - Good lad.
還有一點  黑鬍子
On to it, then. Blackbeard.
-他有什麼習慣  -大多待在他房間
- What are his habits?  - Stays mostly to his cabin.
是的  基本不出來
That's right, mostly to his cabin.
-對  但他一旦出來  -他沒出來過
- Yes, but when he comes out...  - He don't really come out.
他肯定會出來
He must come out sometime.
從沒露面過  沒有
Not really, no.
你們中有誰和他出過海嗎
Any of you sail with him before?
-沒有  沒有  -從來沒有
- No, no.  - I've never.
絕對沒有
Definitely not.
-你們有人見過他嗎  -沒有
- Any of you seen him before?  - Not really, no.
他待在房間  沒人和他出過海
Stays to his cabin, no one sailed with him,
沒人見過他
no one's seen him...
好消息  先生們  這不是黑鬍子的船
Good news, gentlemen. This is not Blackbeard's ship.
這不是安娜王后復仇號
This is not the Queen Anne's Revenge.
不  這是安娜王后復仇號  千真萬確
No, this be the Queen Anne's Revenge, right enough.
你怎麼知道
How do you know?
我見過船尾的船名
I've seen the name, on the back of the ship.
先生們  我的難兄難弟們
Gentlemen, sirs, fellow conscriptees...
你們被徹頭徹尾地騙了
...you have been monstrously deceived.
-我們被騙了  -是的
- We are decepted, then?  - Yes.
他們從沒告訴過你們目的地
You've nay been informed of a destination.
死亡正等著我們
Death lies before us
因為我們要開往不老泉
as we sail for the Fountain of Youth.
這下我們就慘了  兄弟們
It would be a sorry plight, mates.
-死亡  毫無疑問  -那堿O惡靈的殿堂
- Death, for certain.  - The garden of darkened souls.
-我們活不了多久了  -除非
- Untimely our ends will be.  - Unless...
我們要佔領這條船
...we take the ship.
那就這麼幹吧  就現在
We take the ship, then. Now!
去啊
Go on, then.
-來幫忙  水手們  -給他們
- Help me, shipmates!  - Give it to 'em!
-醒醒  船是我們的了  -來吧
- Wake up! It's ours!  - Come on!
起來  起來
Get up! Off your backside!
-別黏糊了  -分給他們  小子
- Get off your fannies!  - Take it to them, lads!
幫我  反抗
Help me! Fight!
傑克
Jack.
如果我在做夢  你帶著劍穿著靴子也無妨
If this is a dream, you can keep the sword and boots on.
-如果不是  -你在做夢
- If it's not...  - It's a dream.
不  不是
No, it's not!
我想我該提醒你下  我們要佔領這艘船
I thought I should give you fair warning, we're taking the ship.
不是針對你
Nothing personal.
我覺得這樣對你有好處
Think you might be better off if you just...
如果你能別管這事的話
...stay out of it.
醜八怪
Boggit.
混蛋
Wretch!
你是敵是友
You're either with us or against us!
非敵非友
I am not with you, neither am I against you!
這不是自相矛盾嗎
Can he do that?
他信教  信教的人都這樣
He's religious. I believe it's required.
受死吧  你們這幫笨頭笨腦的蠢貨
Fight to the bitter end, you cack-handed deck apes!
抓住他  弟兄們  綁緊他
Take him, men. Tie him down tight!
船是我們的了
The ship is ours!
先生們
Gentlemen.
你們讓我很困惑
I be placed in a bewilderment.
我正在堶悼薿
There I were, resting,
突然聽到甲板上傳來不和諧的吵鬧聲
and upon a sudden, I hear an ungodly row on deck.
水手們擅離職守
Sailors abandon their posts
無故缺勤
without orders, without leave.
桅桿前的兄弟
Men before the mast,
想把船據為己有
taking the ship for themselves.
怎麼回事  大副
What be that, First Mate?
-有人叛亂  船長  -什麼
- Mutiny, Captain.  - Again?
-叛亂  -明白了
- Mutiny!  - Aye.
叛亂
Mutiny.
那叛亂者的下場是什麼
And what fate befalls mutineers?
我們知道該怎麼做吧
Now, we know the answer to that, do we not?
把叛亂者都吊起來
Mutineers hang!
船長  我想舉報一場叛亂
Captain, I wish to report a mutiny.
我能指名道姓
I can name fingers and point names.
不需要  史派羅先生
No need, Mr. Sparrow.
他們是羊群  而你  是牧羊人
They are sheep. You, their shepherd.
我有說過嗎  船長  你女兒是個美女
Have I mentioned, sir, what a lovely daughter you have?
你小子死前還挺有眼福
A fitting last sight for a doomed soul.
等等  父親  我們需要他
Remember, Father. We need him.
如果我不時常殺個人
If I don't kill a man every now and then,
-他們會忘了我是誰  -懦夫
- they forget who I am.  - Coward!
他們不會忘
They do not forget.
你的船員們把你看做惡魔
Your crew sees you for the miscreant you are.
無論你殺多少人  你都是個懦夫
A coward, no matter how many you slay.
一天之中  我兩次感到困惑
Twice in one day, I find myself in a bewilderment.
你不是困惑  你是恐懼
You are not bewildered, you are afraid.
你不敢走正義之路
You dare not walk the
光明之路
path of righteousness, the way of the light.
不  牧師  事實比這簡單得多
No, sir. The truth is it be much simpler than all that.
-我就是個壞人  -沒錯
- I am a bad man.  - That, too.
我也能殺了你  傳教士
I might have to kill you too, catechist.
-不  -就跟她老媽一個樣
- No!  - All Latin blood like her mother.
父親  我求求你
Father, I beg you.
我又忘了這傳教士為什麼還活著了
There I be again, forgetting why the missionary is here.
我女兒擔心我的靈魂  或是我剩下的靈魂
My daughter fears for my soul, or what's left of it.
你真想救贖我嗎  孩子
You truly wish to save me, my child?
所有靈魂都能被救贖
Every soul can be saved.
真的嗎  年輕的牧師
Be that true, young cleric?
是的  雖然我覺得你的希望渺茫
Yes. Though you I see as a bit of a long shot.
不過  我仍然為
Still, I pray for every
這艘地獄之船上所有不幸的靈魂祈禱
unfortunate soul on this hell-bound vessel.
你的信念讓我放下武器
You disarm me with your faith.
八擊鍾
Eight bells!
剛才是哪個倒霉鬼在放哨
Which of you unfortunate souls stood watch?
-是我  我在放哨  -炮手
- I did. I stood watch. - Gunner.
你
You?
是的
Aye.
廚子
The cook.
非常好  放下大艇
Perfect. Lower the longboat!
亮出大炮
Bring her about!
為什麼要這樣
Why do you do this?
這是叛變  規矩必須遵守
Mutiny. Our laws be clear.
規矩允許船長網開一面
Our laws allow the Captain to show leniency.
我給了他決定自己命運的機會
I have given this man a chance to determine his fate,
這可不是人人都能有的
a gift not afforded to all.
喂  你
Oh, you now.
現在來瞧瞧你的祈禱有沒有用
Chance to show the worth of your prayers.
祈禱他從魔鬼手中得到...拯救
Pray he be delivered from... evil?
發射
Course made!
住手  給他個機會  給你自己...
Stop. Give that man a chance. Give yourself a...
知道我什麼時候覺得最接近造物主嗎
You know when I feel closest to our Maker?
當我看到苦難  傷痛和苦惱
When I see suffering, pain and anguish.
世界的真實面貌就會顯現
That's when the true design of this world is revealed.
當苦難和悲劇發生之時
And I see it revealed when in times of hardship and tragedy,
需要的人會得到善意和同情
kindness and compassion are shown to those in need.
也許你該祈禱他不受傷害  對吧
Perhaps you should pray for him to be unharmed, yes?
-求求你  還有希望  -再來一次
- Please, there's still hope... - Again!
其實我對不老泉沒半點興趣
I actually have no interest in the Fountain whatsoever,
所以  如果你決心已定
so, if your heart is set,
可以隨便把我扔在哪
you may drop me off anywhere you like.
可以了  舵手
That'll be all, Quartermaster.
你的花言巧語讓人很難看清你的真面目
Your words surround you like fog and make you hard to see.
那你呢  了不起的黑鬍子
And what of you, the mighty Blackbeard?
他們說你被砍了頭  但是身體
Beheaded they say. Still, your body swam
繞船游了三圈  又回到船上
three times around your ship, then climbed back onboard.
而你現在  用恐懼震懾人心
And here you are, running scared.
-恐懼  -所以你要去不老泉
- Scared. - To the Fountain.
舵手可以預見未來
The Quartermaster sees things before they happen.
他預見了我的死亡  命運已經決定
He has foreseen my death, and so the fates have spoken.
命運之網已經張開
The threads of destiny woven.
你對命運的關注太荒謬了  夥計
You have a ridiculously high regard for fate, mate.
-你呢  -我
- And you? - Me?
我對所有預言都持懷疑態度  包括我的
I'm skeptical of predicting any future... which includes me.
和命運抗爭是愚蠢的
It'd be foolish to battle fate,
不過我想要愚弄它
but I'd be tempted to cheat it.
我會到達不老泉  而你會帶我去
I will reach the Fountain. You will lead me.
除了叛變  那把刀已經沒更大用處了
That knife will serve you no better than the mutiny you devised.
叛變很成功
Mutiny served me well.
給我贏得了謁見你的機會
It gained me an audience with you.
是的
Aye.
來警告你
To warn you.
關於你的大副
Regarding your first mate,
她謊報了自己的真實身份
who pretends to be persons she is not.
繼續說
Do tell.
她不是你的女兒
She is not your daughter.
你怎麼敢這麼說我的血脈
You dare to speak thusly of my flesh and blood?
先生  這女人精通騙術
Sir, the woman is consummate in the art of deception.
我知道
I know.
是我不小心將她送上了邪路
As I mostly unwittingly set her on her wicked path.
當然也不能否認
Though I cannot claim credit
她極有天分
for her existing abundance of natural talent.
安琪莉卡  我親愛的女兒
Angelica. My beloved daughter,
我這輩子幹的唯一一件好事
the one true good thing I have done in this life,
你卻聲稱自己把她毀了
and you claim to be the one who corrupted her?
先生  她是純粹的魔鬼
Sir, what she is is pure evil.
比野獸還要可怕
More to be feared than a wild beast.
咬牙切齒的飢餓野獸
Hungry wild beast with gnashing teeth.
充滿仇恨  地獄般飢渴  野獸...
Vengeful, hungry from hell, beast...
-父親  -寶貝
- Father? - Sweetness!
你不用傷害他  父親
No need to hurt him, Father.
他會幫我們  對吧  傑克
He will help us. Won't you, Jack?
你看  即使是現在  她也惦記著你
You see? Even now, she attends to your welfare,
即使你在這編造謊言挑撥離間
giving lie to the claims you make of her.
你會帶我們去不老泉吧
You will lead us to the Fountain. Yes?
換種說法
Put another way.
如果我不能按時到達不老泉
If I do not make it to the Fountain in time...
那你也別想活命
neither will you.
我馬上
I'll have a wee look-see
去看一眼海圖  行嗎
at those charts straight away then, shall I?
先生
Sir.
-什麼事  -船長
- Aye? - Captain, sir,
我很不情願地向您匯報  長官
I am unhappy to report rumors, sir,
關於我們的目的地  船員之間有了謠言
among the crew, as to our destination.
閉嘴  走開
Shut your trap and make way.
-我叫你走開  -沒有不敬的意思  長官
- That's the way of it, then. - No disrespect, sir.
他們怕什麼  說出來  告訴我
What do the men fear? Say it. Speak the words.
白浪灣
Whitecap Bay.
好吧  白浪灣
Aye, Whitecap Bay.
沒用的水手都害怕這個名字
And every worthless seaman fears the name,
自然而然
and rightly so,
但沒人知道為什麼  也沒人敢問
though few know why or dare to ask.
傳說是真的嗎
Be the stories true?
說說是什麼讓你這麼心驚膽戰  吉布斯
Say what robs you of your staunch heart, Gibbs,
不然的話就別危言聳聽
or forever leave it to the wider fields of fancy.
美人魚  船長
Mermaids, Captain.
對  美人魚
Aye. Mermaids.
食屍鬼  魔鬼魚  迫切渴望著人肉
Sea ghouls, devil fish, dreadful in hunger for flesh of man.
美人魚的地盤  是我們的必經之路
Mermaid waters, that be our path.
堅守你的靈魂  吉布斯
Cling to your soul, Gibbs,
因為美人魚會將靈魂以外的東西
as mermaids be given to take the rest...
吃干抹淨
to the bone.
穩住  穩住  鼓起勇氣
Steady! Steady, men! Find your courage,
不然就準備屈服於恐懼吧
or be ready to purpose your fear!
快逃命吧
Save yourselves!
-有人落水了  -不  是個逃兵
- Man overboard! - Nay! A deserter.
-改變航向  -不
- Come about. - Nay!
先生們  我不再問任何人
Gentlemen, I shall not ask any more of any man than what
他能怎麼樣
that man can deliver,
我只想問  難道我們不是國王的子民嗎
but I do ask this: Are we not king's men?
是
Aye.
-執行國王的任務  -是
- On the king's mission? - Aye.
西班牙人經過我們的時候
I did not note any fear in
在他們眼堨i沒有任何恐懼
the eyes of the Spanish as they passed us by.
-難道我們不是國王的子民嗎  -是
- Are we not king's men? - Aye!
這就對了  堅守崗位  打起精神
Aye! Hands all off, and bear away!
一往無前  直奔白浪灣
Stave on ahead to Whitecap Bay!
繼續前進  白浪灣
Bear on, Whitecap Bay!
過來
Come.
來點酒嗎
Little drink?
美酒  音樂  燭光
Wine, music, candlelight.
這場景似曾相識  傑克
I think we've traveled down this road before, Jack.
是的
Yes, we have.
我記得很清楚
I remember it well.
搖擺  舞動  旋轉  纏綿
Winding, twisting and turning, gyrating, writhing.
無盡的纏綿
Incessant writhing.
還記得聖多米尼克嗎
Do you recall Saint Dominique?
馬提尼克島
La Martinique.
我在聖多米尼克想殺你來著
I tried to kill you in Saint Dominique.
管他呢
Either or.
作為大副這太不合適了
Hardly appropriate for a first mate.
我是第一個嗎  我真好奇
Was I the first? I've often wondered.
你有所求的時候總是這麼迷人  傑克
You can be so charming when you want something, Jack.
問題在於發現你想要什麼
The trick is finding out what.
真相  對吧
The truth, then, is it?
黑鬍子已經達到目的了
Blackbeard has served his purpose.
我們可以一起去不老泉
You and I can go to the Fountain together,
我們可以共同名揚四海
where we shall bathe one another in equal shares of fame
還可以花樣百出  縱情享樂
and other assorted debaucheries.
我告訴你怎樣進行不老泉的儀式
And I'll tell you the ritual of the Fountain.
對  瀆神儀式
Yes. The profane ritual.
我能相信你嗎  傑克
Can I trust you, Jack?
-我需要你支持我  -最親愛的安琪莉卡
- I need you on my side. - Oh, my dearest Angelica.
我們現在親密無間  我的愛
You and I are as thick as thieves, love.
告訴我方法
Tell me the rules.
不老泉的泉水
Water from the Fountain of Youth.
美人魚閃爍的眼淚
The shimmering tear of a mermaid.
龐塞·德萊昂的聖盃
The silver chalices of Ponce de Leon.
有了這些東西...
With these items...
-什麼  -有了這些東西
- Yes? - With these items,
你就能得到另一個人的所有壽命  傑克
you may take all the years of life from another, Jack.
你知道這意味著什麼
You know what that means.
我們不能自己去  你和我
We cannot go alone, you and I.
儀式需要一個祭品
The ritual requires a victim.
-這太不幸了  -確實
- That is unfortunate. - Yes, it is.
我發現自己不是很想去不老泉了
I find my desire for the Fountain greatly lessened.
不過船上確實有你想要的東西
But there is something onboard you do want.
黑鬍子發現怎麼辦
What about Blackbeard?
他在海圖室  我們得快點
He's in the chart room. We'll have to be quick.
他把這些船當作戰利品
He keeps each ship as a prize.
你幫我  我就讓你選一艘
You help me, and I promise you your pick.
不過我想我知道你會選哪艘
Though I think I know the one you will choose.
黑珍珠號在瓶子
The Black Pearl in a bottle?
為什麼黑珍珠號會在瓶子
Why is the Black Pearl in a bottle?
它縮小後更討人厭
He's even more annoying in miniature.
-成交嗎  傑克  -安琪莉卡  我瞭解你
- Do we have a deal, Jack? - Angelica, I know you.
你不會向無辜的人竊取生命
You are not going to steal the life of some innocent man.
那個獨腿男人怎麼樣
What about the one-legged man?
我需要壽命  傑克
I need years, Jack.
不是給我  是給我父親
Not for me. For my father.
我真是黑鬍子的女兒
I am truly the daughter of Blackbeard.
你騙人騙得分不清現實了  親愛的
You've fallen for your own con, love.
不  他確實是我父親
No, he is my father.
我對你說的謊言其實不是謊言
The lies I told you were not lies.
你用真相對我撒謊
You lied to me by telling me the truth?
-對  -真不錯
- Yes. - That's very good.
-可以借用嗎  -反正你總會用
- May I use that? - I'm sure you will, anyway.
當然了
Of course I will.
所以  你不會放棄是吧
So, will you not give up this quest?
我想有個父親  傑克  以前從沒有過
I want a father, Jack. I haven't had one.
安琪莉卡  你父親  黑鬍子
Angelica, your father, Blackbeard...
是個魔鬼
he is evil,
一旦有機會他就會殺了你
and he will kill you given the chance.
-他已經沒救了  -你憑什麼
- He cannot be saved. - And who are you to set
決定誰能被救贖
the limits on redemption?
你偷走了我的年華  傑克  你欠我的
You stole years of my life, Jack. You owe me.
你這是要害死自己
And you are en route to getting yourself killed,
我不會就這麼袖手旁觀
and I am not inclined to stand by and watch.
白浪灣
Whitecap Bay!
全員集合  放下大艇
All hands on deck! Set to the longboats!
把網展平
Lay'em out flat!
別弄亂  得為我們的貴賓弄得漂亮點
No tangles. Make'em look pretty for our dainty guests.
我們需要光  很亮的光
We're gonna need light. A lot of light.
過來
Come!
聞見了嗎  鯨魚油  燒起來像神跡
Smell that? Whale oil. Stuff burns like a miracle from God.
-能讓它亮起來嗎  -英國人造的
- Can you make it work? - Made by the English.
別抱太大希望
Let's not get our hopes up.
月亮才剛剛露出一牙
The old moon in the arms of the new one.
夏季的第一彎新月
First of the summer.
獵取美人魚眼淚的完美時機
Perfect for hunting a mermaid's tear.
我們完了  她們會被人造光吸引過來
We're doomed. They be drawn to man-made light.
-鯊魚嗎  -比鯊魚還可怕  孩子
- Sharks? - Worse than sharks, boy.
一小時之內美人魚就會到這來
There'll be mermaids upon us within the hour,
記住我的話  我們是誘餌
you mark my words. And we're the bait.
聽說美人魚的吻
I heard it said a kiss from a mermaid
能保護水手不被淹死
protects a sailor from drowning.
別犯傻了孩子  美人魚全是雌性
Don't be a fool! Mermaids are all female, son,
像夢中的天堂一樣美麗
and lovely as a dream of heaven.
但當她們露出本性  據說
But when it comes time to churn butter, so to speak,
她們會把水手拖出船外
they snatch a sailor out of a boat
或者拖下甲板  總之是這樣
or off the deck of a ship, have their way,
然後把他們拖到海底  淹死吃掉
and then the sailors are pulled to bottom and drowned and eaten.
或者有時候  正好相反
Or, sometimes, the other way around.
-唱歌  -什麼
- Sing. - What?
她們喜歡聽人唱歌
They like to hear singing.
我叫瑪莉亞
My name is Maria
我是商人的女兒
A merchant's daughter fair
-大點聲  -我離開雙親
- Louder. - And I have left my parents
每一年賺上三千英鎊
And 3,000 pounds a year
我的心被丘比特射中
My heart is pierced by Cupid
我對金子也不屑一顧
I disdain all glittering gold
只有快樂勇敢的水手
There is nothing can console me
能讓我的心得到慰藉
But my jolly sailor bold
我的心被丘比特射中
My heart is pierced by Cupid
我對金子也不屑一顧
I disdain all glittering gold
只有快樂勇敢的水手
There is nothing can console me
能讓我的心得到慰藉
But my jolly sailor bold
神啊  救救我吧
Lord save me.
看  看那邊
Man, look. Look there.
你會嚇到她
You'll scare her off!
那可真是謝天謝地
Aye, and good riddance!
你會說話嗎
Can you talk?
會
Yes.
你真漂亮
You're beautiful.
-是你唱的歌嗎  -是
- Are you the one who sings? - Aye.
你是我快樂勇敢的水手嗎
Are you my jolly sailor bold?
-是  我是  -史考姆  清醒點
- Aye, that I be. - Scrum, comport yourself!
大伙們  我短暫而悲慘的一生中
Boys! There ain't much been given to me
從來沒得到過什麼  真的
in my brief, miserable life, there's the truth in it.
但是  天哪  我現在得說
But, by God, I'll have it said
史考姆要得到一個真正的美人魚之吻了
that Scrum had himself a kiss from a proper mermaid!
我的心被丘比特射中
My heart is pierced by Cupid
我對金子也不屑一顧
I disdain all glittering gold
只有快樂勇敢的水手
There is nothing can console me
能讓我的心得到慰藉
But my jolly sailor bold
來吧美麗的少女們
Come all ye pretty fair maids
不論你是誰
Whoever you may be
愛著那快樂勇敢
Who love a jolly sailor bold
征服驚濤駭浪的水手
That ploughs the raging sea
我的心被丘比特射中
My heart is pierced by Cupid
我對金子也不屑一顧
I disdain all glittering gold
只有快樂勇敢的水手
There is nothing can console me
能讓我的心得到慰藉
But my jolly sailor bold
我的心被丘比特射中
My heart is pierced by Cupid
我對金子也不屑一顧
I disdain all glittering gold
只有快樂勇敢的水手
There is nothing can console me
能讓我的心得到慰藉
But my jolly sailor bold
都出來  開始了
Out upon it! It has begun!
點起來
Light'em up!
鼓起勇氣  把她們趕到岸邊
Muster your courage! Drive'em to shore!
把網撒進水  快
Nets into the water! Quickly!
撤退  所有人上岸  保命要緊
Retreat, all, to land! For your lives!
快撤退
Retreat, I say!
膽小鬼  回水堨h
Cowards! Back in the water!
岸上沒地方給你們躲  我說到做到
There be no refuge on land! On my word!
來
come on!
我們抓到一個
We got one!
我戀愛了
I'm in love!
查看傷員
Check the wounded!
看能不能找到還活著的美人魚
See if you can find one mermaid still alive!
快來  搭把手
Come, give a hand!
幹得漂亮  水手
Well done, sailor.
大家都看見了嗎
Did everyone see that?
下次我絕對不這麼玩了
Because I will not be doing it again.
回船  駛向安全地帶  快點
Back to the ship. We head for a protected cove. Now.
-老天  這難道是...  -美人魚
- Lord. Is that? - Mermaid.
-放棄這瘋狂任務吧  -不行
- Give up this madness now. - I cannot.
你走在沙灘上的時候
Ever walk on the beach,
會不會回頭看自己留下的腳印們
look back and see your footsteps in the sand?
就是這感覺  不過我的腳印們朝向前方
It's like that, except the footsteps lie before me.
-是腳印  沒有"們"  -白浪灣  長官
- Footstep, actually. - Whitecap Bay, sir.
我們必須加快步伐
We must hasten.
咱們用走的  吉布斯  需要有人帶路
We travel by foot. Gibbs, I require a heading.
-但是長官  我們的船員...  -他們已經死了
- But, sir, the men. - They be dead already.
-聽起來還沒死  -真的嗎
- They don't sound dead. - Oh, is that so?
我只聽到海鷗築巢的聲音而已
Well, I hear nothing but seagulls nesting.
你聽見什麼聲音了  格洛夫斯先生
What is it that you hear, Mr. Groves?
海鷗...在築巢
Seagulls... nesting.
-沒有別的了  -領路  吉布斯
- Nothing more. - Heading, Gibbs?
老天
My God.
你不領頭  我就領走你的頭
Your head or my heading.
任選其一  我無所謂
I'll have me one or t'other, I don't care which.
全體前進
All hands, forward!
-該你上場了  史派羅  -這樣真有必要嗎
- It's to you now, Sparrow. - Was that really necessary?
你最好不要知道我的船的下落
Best you not know the exact whereabouts of my ship.
-我可是個謹慎的人  -我也是
- I be a cautious man. - So be I.
但我最想知道的是
What I want first...
龐塞·德萊昂的船在哪
...is Ponce De Leon's ship.
我們為什麼要帶她一起走
Why is it we've got to bring her along?
我們需要新鮮的眼淚
Because tears don't keep. We need them fresh.
這什麼儀式來著
What is the ritual again?
泉中水和人魚淚
Water from the Fountain and a mermaid's tear?
還有兩隻銀聖盃
And two silver chalices.
一杯有眼淚  一杯沒有
One cup with a tear, one without.
就是兩杯都有水  一杯埵陴\
So, one with a tear and water in both?
還真夠麻煩的  是吧
Quite complicated, is it not?
兩杯都有水  其中一杯有眼淚
Both get water. One gets a tear.
喝那杯帶眼淚的人
The person who drinks the water with the tear
能獲得喝另一杯的人的所有壽命
gets all the years of life from the other.
那是多少年
How many years?
所有已生之年
All the years that they have lived,
和剩下的未活之年  如果命運發慈悲的話
and they could have lived, if fate had been kinder.
牧師
Clergyman.
萬一萬一我遭遇啥不測
On the off chance that this does not go well for me,
我想跟你說
I would like it noted here and now
我願意相信你那些有的沒的
that I am fully prepared to believe in whatever I must,
讓我也能進那個好地方
so that I may be welcomed into that place
就是那些虛偽的老好人去的地方  懂?
where all the goody-goodies get to go. Savvy?
我們有個術語  傑克  你可以皈依
We have a word for that, Jack. You can convert.
我是想等到萬不得已再說
I was thinking more of an as-needed basis.
舵手
Quartermaster!
-怎麼  -她不能呼吸了
- Aye? - She cannot breathe!
-箱埵酗  -她需要空氣
- She has water. - She needs air!
-把蓋子打開  -她會逃走
- Open this. - She will escape.
-你會殺了她  -我支持傳教士
- You're killing her. - I support the missionary's position.
看見了嗎
See?
繼續前進
Onward.
和我想的一樣  此路不通
Just as I thought. Not this way!
應該朝這邊走  不是嗎
This is the way, isn't it?
方向當然對  但是應該從東邊繞過去
'Course it is, but we should go around to the east.
那就不是去拿聖盃的路線了
That would take us out of the path of the chalices.
-我們可以繞回去  -沒那麼多時間
- Well, then we'll circle back. - There is no time.
是你非要帶著那美人魚
You're the one who insisted on bringing the bloody mermaid.
-那你還組織叛變  -你走得還真像個娘們
- Well, the mutiny didn't help. - You walk like a girl.
-你想見識見識  -必須有人過去
- You would know. - Someone must go.
你是說分頭行動
You mean split up?
你是說有人跳下去吧  我也想看人跳下去
You mean jump? This I cannot wait to see.
史派羅跳下去  找到船  拿回聖盃
Sparrow will go. Find the ship, retrieve the chalices.
史派羅  你覺得他還會回來嗎
Sparrow? What makes you think he will come back?
是啊  你覺得他還會回來嗎
Yes, what makes you think he will come back?
我們不能相信他  爸爸  讓我去
We cannot trust him, Father. I'll go.
她說她去
She'll go.
離泉水還有多遠
How much farther to the Fountain?
我沒有時間了
I'm running out of time.
大概沿著河  朝北走一天
About a day's march north, following that river,
就會看到一堆水塘  那就快到了
you'll get to a series of pools. Then you're close.
跳吧
You will go.
我就知道會變成這樣
I was sure it would come to this.
你們知道站在高處時
You know that feeling you get
有時候會有那麼一種
sometimes when you're standing in a high place?
特想往下跳的感覺嗎
Sudden urge to jump?
我就沒有這種感覺
I don't have it.
我需要聖盃
I need those chalices.
開槍吧  還省得我自己跳了
Shoot. Save me the bother of the fall.
你跳下去  然後來找我
You will go. You will return...
要不然  我就殺了她
...or I will kill her.
你不會殺自己的女兒
You won't kill your own daughter.
舵手  再給我拿六把手槍
Quartermaster, get me six more pistols,
卸了子彈  留兩支槍埵酗l彈
remove the shot from all but two,
別告訴我是哪兩支
but do not tell me which two.
該你選了  史派羅
You get to choose, Mr. Sparrow.
不對
No.
-這個  -你確定
- Yes. - You're sure?
當然確定
'Course I am.
再來
Again.
拜託  根本就沒子彈
Please, they're not even loaded.
再來
Again.
你要是那麼想殺了她
If you're so keen on killing her,
-為啥不讓她跳  -什麼
- why don't you just let her jump? - What?
如果你跳下去  跌死了
If you jump and die,
就輪到她了
then she will have her chance.
再來
Again.
如果我跳下去  有活得可能嗎
...if I jump, will I survive?
玩偶給我
The doll.
-這樣你也許就死不了  -簡直胡扯  我跳
- Yes, now you will survive. - This is nonsense! I'm going!
濕了  又濕了
Wet. Wet again.
繼續出發  向北走
We go on. Due north to the Fountain.
演得不錯  父親
Well played, Father.
您早就知道哪兩把槍有子彈吧
You knew which guns were loaded, right?
當然  親愛的
Of course, my love.
要是有地圖就好了
Be nice to have a map about now.
或者有艘船也行
Or a ship.
站住  不許動
Stop! Hold very still.
不能讓它碰到你
Ye dare not let it touch your skin.
怎麼  上了年紀的人有點愛好不行嗎
What? What be wrong with an older man having a hobby?
停下幹什麼  趕緊走
What are you stopping for, eh? Push on!
-趕緊走  -死了之後有你睡的
- Push on! - You can sleep when you're dead.
趕緊走
Push on!
幸運女神繼續眷顧我們
Fortune continues to favor us.
聖地亞哥
The Santiago.
龐塞·德萊昂曾讓它享譽一時
Famously captained by Ponce de Leon.
沒有圍觀群眾
There's no one there.
好吧
Right, then.
不能停下
We must not stop.
你得自己走
You will walk.
我不會走
I cannot.
不走就得死
Walk or die.
環著我的脖子
Put your arms around me.
-我沒要你幫我  -但你需要我的幫助
- I do not ask for help. - But you need it.
-不是趕路嗎  -別拖後腿
- We're in a hurry, yes? - Do not fall behind.
在這休息一會
Hold here 'til I say!
你真美
Such beauty.
你一定是上帝創造的
Surely you're one of God's own creations,
不是那些未能踏上諾亞方舟的
and not a descendant of those dark creatures
黑暗而墮落生物的後代
who found no refuge on the Ark.
如此的美
Such beauty...
卻又致命
...and yet deadly.
-致命?  不  -你攻擊了我
- Deadly? No. - You attacked me.
不  你不同
No. You are different.
不同嗎
Different?
不是嗎  你保護了我
Are you not? You protect.
是嗎
Did you?
你把我推開了
You pushed me down out of the way.
-你看見不老泉了嗎  -沒有  但已經很近了
- You see the Fountain? - No, but we are close.
帶上那生物  捂上她的頭
Bring the creature. Cover its head.
她有名字
She has a name!
請講
Pray tell.
她是塞蕾娜
She is Syrena.
龐塞·德萊昂
Ponce de Leon.
四十個海盜連著四十個晚上夢見的財寶
If 40 pirates dreamt 40 nights of treasure,
也趕不上這屋堛滌]寶
it would not match the contents of this room.
是你
You.
-你  -不
- You. - No...
-你  -是我先來的
-...you. - I was here first.
-你為什麼來這  -黑鬍子派我來的
- You, why are you here? - Blackbeard sent me.
-你呢  -銀聖盃
- Why are you? - Silver chalices
-為我的陛下  -得了
- for my royal liege. - Oh, please.
後退  後退  我們必須保證船的平衡
Back, back! We have to balance it out!
這船會滑下去
The whole ship will slide!
那好吧
Right, then.
那要是我們各選一樣差不多沉的東西呢
What if we each choose an item of approximately equal weight?
放回去
Put it back!
我們什麼也不能動
We touch nothing!
那個呢
What about that?
聖盃
The chalices.
憑什麼你先看
Oi! Why do you get to look first?
那好吧
Fine, then.
-一起看  -一起看
- Together. - Together.
石頭
Rocks.
那些西班牙佬
The Spanish.
夥計  他們比我們早來一步
They're ahead of us, mate.
我該看看那地圖  要是我想的沒錯...
I shall have a look at that map. If it's what I fear...
他們怎麼會把這東西留下
I wonder why they left this behind.
別碰那地圖
Don't touch the map.
他們知道了路線
They know the path,
但我也知道他們最可能在哪駐營
but I can also see where they'll most likely make camp.
傑克
Jack!
吉布斯  我正要去監獄救你來著
Gibbs, I was just on me way to break you out of jail.
你偷了我的地圖
You stole my map.
好了  行動
Right. Best be started.
美人魚
Mermaids.
小心  這些水塘很深
Careful, these pools run deep.
如果她逃了  就全完了  舵手
If she escapes, all is lost. Quartermaster.
看  看好了
Look. Look!
她被繫在樁上  在太陽下暴曬
Staked out to die, to dry in the sun.
身體一半在水中  不夠活命
Only half in the water. Not enough to live,
只能慢慢死去
but just enough to make the dying slow.
考慮一下吧
Think on it.
你的族群被殺害  只是為了眼淚
Your people, murdered, harvested for their tears.
塞蕾娜  你難道不想哭嗎
Syrena, won't you cry?
你也難逃一死
All die, even you.
-快了  -聽著
- Soon, I hear. - Listen...
聽好了
Listen.
你難道聽不到你姐妹們的呼喊
Can you not hear your sisters scream?
聽不到嗎
Do you not hear them?
我們只需要一滴眼淚
We need but one tear.
下賤的生物
Vile creature!
-一根根切掉她的手指  -掐死她
- Chop off her fingers, one by one! - Choke her!
從眼睛底下挖出眼淚來
Cut out the tears from behind the eyes!
你看得下去嗎
Where's your voice in this?
也許日出後她就轉變心意了
Maybe she'll have a change of heart when the sun rises.
對  她會灼傷  但我等不到日出
Oh, aye, she will burn, but I cannot wait for the sun.
也許我們應該生把火
Perhaps we should build a fire.
-不行  -不准質疑我  教士
- No. - Do not contest me, cleric.
-你們不准折磨她  -我們只需要一滴眼淚
- You will not torture her. - We need only one tear.
可以的話  我會把她的鱗一片一片剝下來
I will tear every scale from her body one by one if I see fit.
要是你不滿意  祈禱去吧
If that displeases you, go pray.
我錯了  並不是所有靈魂都能拯救  你無藥可救
I was wrong. Not every soul can be saved. Yours cannot.
看啊  各位  曾經有信仰的人
Behold, gentlemen, a man formerly of faith.
你說她是卑賤的生物  但你還趕不上她萬分之一
That vile creature, as you call her, is worth a hundred of you.
喲  你關心她
Oh, you care for her?
你愛她
You fancy her.
我看得一清二楚  別否認這份感情
And do not deny what is clear to my eyes.
問題是
Question is...
她愛不愛你
...does she fancy you?
老天爺  她還真愛你  走運了
My God, she does. We are in luck!
流下一滴眼淚
Bring forth a tear...
或見證這可憐生命的消亡
...or witness the death of this poor soul.
塞蕾娜  如果你能流下一滴眼淚
Syrena, if you could manage a tear,
我將萬分感激
I would be grateful.
悲傷  是有
Sadness, yes,
-但卻並不悲痛  -別髒了您的手  父親
- but no sorrow... yet. - Not by your hand, Father!
時間不等人  舵手
Time and tide wait for none. Quartermaster.
美人魚還真難搞
Aye, mermaids are tough.
都夠難搞的
The lot of them.
把她綁起來  把這屍體處理了
Tie her up like the others. And get rid of this.
-你有信心嗎  -有
- You are confident? - Yes.
我是女人  她也是
I am a woman. So is she.
你這是演的哪一出  傑克  和巴博薩搭起伙來了
What's your play, Jack? Throwing in with Barbossa.
有個姑娘...
There is a girl...
...一個女性...異性
...A female... of the opposite sex.
-姑娘不是異性是什麼  -也許應該說是少女
- When is there not? - Perhaps I should say "Damsel."
-你還救少女嗎  -萬事總有第一次
- You're rescuing a damsel? - Well, there's a first.
但有可能我讓這個所謂的少女
Yes, but it's just that I may have caused said damsel
-幾個月前受傷了  -不奇怪
- some manner of harm many moons ago. - Out with it.
吉布斯  她是個塞維利亞的女人
Gibbs, this is the woman from Seville.
你裝作喜歡她
Ah, you pretended to love her,
結果你離開她  傷了她的心
then you left her and broke her heart.
比這更糟  我也許是  簡短地說  就是
Worse. I may have had, briefly, mind you...
-造成了她內心波動  -波動
- ...stirrings. - Stirrings?
-波動  -什麼  就是有感情了吧
- Stirrings. - What? Like feelings, you mean?
不不不  不是那個意思  更像是...
No, no, no. Not quite all the way to feelings. More like...
好吧  就是感情  該死的
All right, feelings, damn you.
結果你還是離開了她  夠低級的
And you left her still. That's low.
謝謝
Thank you.
秘密行動
Stealth over force.
接下來我搞定好了  你不太方便
I'll take it from here on account of your condition.
你沒招白蟻吧
You don't have termites, do you?
感謝你的關心  傑克
I appreciate your concern, Jack,
但我還是會盯著你
but I'll be keeping you company all the same.
在這等著  大副  等我指示
Hold here, Lieutenant Commander. Wait for my signal.
那邊那個  就是頭領
There. That one. That be the leader.
記住他的帳篷  那就是...
Make note of his tent because that's where...
等等  老天  那肯定就是聖盃了
No, wait. My God, that must be them right there.
你的劍聞起來很搞笑
Your sword smells funny.
是  我塗了蟾蜍內臟的毒
Aye. Poison from the innards of poisonous toads.
蹭一下  幾分鐘內你就死了
Just a scratch, you're a dead man in minutes.
你能不能別用劍指著我
Would you mind pointing it the other way?
我不喜歡蟾蜍
I don't like toads.
-你在幹嘛  -計劃逃生路線
- What are you doing? - Planning an escape route.
-你不也這樣計劃嗎  -當然
- Isn't that how you do it? - Yes.
不過有時候我只是...即興發揮
Or sometimes I just... improvise.
現在怎麼辦
Now what?
咱們逛出去  慢而堅定
We stroll out, slow and steady.
理所應當一樣
Just like we belong.
-抱歉  塞蕾娜  -菲利普  你還活著
- I'm sorry, Syrena. - Philip, you're alive.
-是  -你來救我嗎
- Yes. - You came for me.
為什麼
Why?
你是不同的吧
You're different, are you not?
你善良  有同情心  是吧
Do you know not of kindness? Compassion?
悲痛才不會讓它們落淚
Tears of sorrow, never.
美人魚太堅強了
Mermaids be too tough for that.
但喜悅的眼淚
But tears of joy...
都說這更有效
They say these be the more potent anyway.
塞蕾娜  我發誓  我並不知情
Syrena, on my word, I had no part in this.
放她走吧  你現在不需要她了
Let her go. You don't need her now.
放她走  沒門
Let her go? No.
把她捆好  讓她自生自滅
Secure her bonds. We leave her with her own.
想出什麼逃跑方案了嗎
How's that escape route working?
展示你隨機應變的時刻到了
Here's your chance to improvise.
我在想呢
I'm attempting it.
大概我能鬆出一只手
I might be able to get a hand loose.
你帶著刀呢  非常好
Oh, you got a knife. That's very good.
比刀還好
Better.
我也要喝
I want one of those.
復仇真是甜美甘洌啊
Here's to revenge. Sweet and clear.
-什麼復仇  -得了吧  赫克托
- Revenge? - Come, come, Hector.
你如果想要那聖盃
If you wanted the chalices,
你會眼睜睜看著它落入他人囊中嗎
you'd seen they were missing and gone.
你在伺機候著黑鬍子
You were lying in wait, for Blackbeard.
喬治國王  私掠船  假髮
King George. Privateer. Wig.
這些伎倆太低級了
Cheap theatrical facade.
-我才不信呢  -那晚你沒在
- I'm not buying it. - You weren't there that night.
黑珍珠沉沒的時候嗎
When the Pearl was lost?
不是沉沒  是被奪走了
Taken, not lost.
我們剛從伊斯島起航就遭到了襲擊
We were off the coast of Hispaniola when we came under attack.
沒有徵兆  沒有警告  也沒有談判
No provocation nor warning nor offer of parley.
上來就是連天的炮火
We were peppered with cannon fire.
隨後  海面翻滾起來
And then the sea beneath the Pearl began to roil.
黑珍珠開始劇烈晃動
The Pearl was pitching and yawing violently.
每塊甲板  每道欄杆
Every plank, every rail,
每根船桿全都開始吱嘎作響
every spar, all at once, began to creak.
帆纜也好像有了生命
The rigging had come to life.
我們的船叛變了
Our own ship turned against us...
纜繩就像毒蛇一樣纏住船員
...tangling the crew, wrapping around 'em like snakes.
纏住我的腿
And wrapping around me leg.
但我的胳膊還能動  劍也還在手
But me arms were free and me sword was to hand.
我才是這船的主人  不是黑鬍子
I am the master of me ship, not Blackbeard.
我才是自己命運的主人  不是黑鬍子
I am the master of my fate, not Blackbeard.
所以我就採取了必要措施
So I did what needed done.
我活了下來
I survived.
也就是說  你不是要找不老泉
So... you're not after the Fountain.
我才不在乎國王的命令
I care not for King George or tavern yarns
還是傳聞說能治癒這瘸腿
that give hope for a healed limb.
但要是能幹掉黑鬍子  叫我犧牲左臂也情願
But I'd give my left arm for a chance at Blackbeard.
-幹嘛不是右臂  -右臂要留著
- Not your right? - I need me good arm
揮舞毒劍  刺穿他的心臟
to drive my poisoned blade through his heart.
看來你的機會來了  夥計
I'll see you get the chance, mate.
犯人逃跑了
The prisoner's escaping.
他逃了  扇形散開  抓住他
He's escaping! Fan out! Find him!
快跑
Go! Go!
別開槍  我要抓活的
Hold your fire! I want him alive!
我想那是信號
I figured that was the signal.
-準備撤離  -敵人很快就追來了
- Go! Prepare to move out! - The enemy is soon upon us.
聖盃的事我很遺憾
I'm sorry about the chalices,
傑克  但我還得赴個約
Jack, but I've an appointment to keep.
-我不會回去  -不用
- I'll not be going back. - No need.
-喝一杯怎麼樣  -到了不老泉再喝
- Shall we have a drink? - We'll drink at the Fountain.
我們每次見面你都要衝我舞刀弄劍嗎
How is it we can never meet without you pointing something at me?
聖盃帶來了嗎  史派羅
You brought the chalices, Sparrow?
當然
Aye. Oi!
-你還帶了個朋友  -是的
- I see you brought a friend. - I did.
那個獨腿海盜也在附近吧
And the one-legged man, he is near. Aye?
是的
Aye.
現在
Now...
在我交出它們之前
Before I go just handing them over,
我有那麼一兩個要求
I do have one or two conditions.
-快說  -首先
- Name them. - Firstly,
我想要回指南針  不不  那是第二個
I'll be having me compass back. No, no, that's secondly.
第一  你要答應
Firstly, upon your word,
絕不會傷害安琪莉卡
you will bring no harm to Angelica.
我不會對你這種人保證什麼  史派羅
I'll make no vows to the likes of you, Sparrow.
但也不妨承認
But it costs me nothing to admit
她永遠不會受到傷害
that she was never in harm's way.
那麼第二條  就是之前的第一條
Secondly then, priorly firstly,
把指南針還我
I will be having me compass back.
拜託了  這是我應得的
Please? I do deserve it.
你知不知道
Do you have any idea how
抓住這頭臭豬有多費勁
difficult it was to catch that filthy pig?
不是大的那頭  是四條腿的那頭
Not the big one, the four-legged one.
謝謝  第三條  鬍子先生
Thank you. And thirdly, Mr. Beard,
有的時候  偶爾
there are times, not very often,
我會回想起自己卑劣的所作所為
when I do reflect upon my heinous misdeeds.
尤其是我對吉布斯先生的做法
Chief among them, I note how poorly I have treated Mr. Gibbs,
-我那忠心的大副  -現在你才說...
- my loyal first mate. - Aye! Now you bring it up...
那會我任由他在監獄受罪  毫不關心
Left him to rot in jail, I did. Didn't care.
現在我也不關心  但問題是你得放他走
Still don't. But, point being, you must let him go free.
-就這樣嗎  -我想是的
- Is that it? - I think so.
快決定  否則豬跑了看你怎麼拿回杯子
Quick, or the pig runs, and good luck getting those chalices.
傑克  如果你不在乎這杯子  那我情願...
Jack, if it's all the same to you, I'd be just as...
成交
Done.
放開那豬吧
Release the swine.
如果你不介意
Perhaps, if you don't mind,
我或許可以跟你們一起...
I could tag along with you folk for a...
這能帶你走向自由  夥計
This will lead you to freedom, mate.
我發誓就在這附近
I could have swore it was somewhere right around here.
我們不能停下
We must not stop.
死路
Dead end.
死路  結束了
Dead. End.
死路
Dead end.
傑克  你知不知道要怎麼走
Jack, I'm starting to think you don't know where you're going.
人們說  沿途風景要勝過目的地
It is not the destination so much as the journey, they say.
請把聖盃給我
Chalices, if you please.
退後
Stand back.
傑克
Jack...
你到底有沒有
...have you ever, in fact...
親眼見過不老泉
...seen with your own eyes... the Fountain of Youth?
抱歉  你說什麼來著
I'm sorry, could you repeat the question, please?
舵手
Quartermaster.
不不
No, no!
等等
Wait, wait! Wait.
生命...之水[西班牙語]
"Aqua... de Vida."
史考姆先生
Master Scrum...
-如果你不介意  -拿著這個嗎
- ...do you mind? - Squire?
真美
So beautiful.
史派羅  我要第一個喝那泉水
Sparrow, I'll be the first to taste those waters.
父親
Father.
獨腿海盜
The one-legged man.
-你把他引來這  -我會那麼做嗎
- You brought him here. - Would I do that?
愛德華·提奇
Edward Teach!
鑒於你在公海犯下的種種罪行
For crimes committed on the high seas,
國王陛下賦予我職權
by the authority granted me by His Majesty the King...
同時我個人也相當樂意
...and with a goodly amount of personal satisfaction...
拘押逮捕你
...I hereby place you in the custody of the court,
你是我的階下囚
and declare you to be my prisoner.
我氣數已盡了吧
My trick's out, is that it?
罪名包括但不限於  海盜行為  通姦叛國
Such crimes do include, but are not limited to, piracy, treason,
蓄意謀殺以及殘酷折磨
murder, torture of the most heinous sort,
包括野蠻奪走一條飽經風霜的右腿
including the brutal theft of one used, twisted, hairy right leg.
你不怕面對這把劍嗎
You... dare face this sword?
這堣S不是你的船  當然不怕
This far away from your ship? Aye.
我能感到後背吹來冰冷的命運之息
Aye. That be the cold breath of fate I feel down my nape.
但老天作證  我要打這最後一戰
But I'll have one last fight, by God.
殺光他們
Kill 'em all!
等一下
Hang on a minute.
我只想弄清一件事
I just... I just need to understand something.
你們要打他們
Right, so, you will fight against them,
他們又要打你們
they will fight against you.
而這只是因為他想要殺他
All on account of him wanting to kill him?
這是什麼邏輯
Where is the sense?
對吧
Exactly.
要我說不如讓他們自己去打
I say, let them fight each other while we lay back,
我們退後觀戰  喝喝酒賭賭錢
watch, have a drink, place some wagers!
好
Aye.
-殺掉他們  -不要憐憫敵人
- Kill 'em! - No quarter!
滾開
Get off me!
史考姆  聖盃
Scrum, the chalices!
帶上眼淚  跟我來
And the tear! Follow!
打啊
Fight!
交出眼淚來  好孩子
Hand it over. The tear. There's a good lad.
我更怕她一些
I'm more afraid of her than I am of you.
交出來  好孩子
Hand it over. There's a good lad.
-把聖盃給我  -抱歉  傑克
- The chalices, if you please. - Sorry, Jack.
我說過我需要壽命  看來用你的就行
I told you, I need years. And now, yours will do.
史考姆
Scrum!
塞蕾娜
Syrena...
主啊  不要帶走她
Oh God, you will not take her.
如果你帶走了她  還她回來吧
If you have taken her, you will give her back.
還她回來
Give her back...
還她回來  求你了
Give her back, please. Please.
我還期待命運給我安排個硬角色呢
I expected fate to put up more of a fight, eh?
你被我打到在地  有什麼好高興的
I will not have that smile on your face as I strike you down.
回頭看看吧  愛德華·提奇
Take a gander, Edward Teach.
吾茲宣佈  這片土地歸偉大的
This land is hereby forever claimed in the glorious name
喬治國王陛下所有...
of His Majesty King George...
找人記錄下那人的英勇行為
Someone make a note of that man's bravery.
小姐  請把聖盃交出來
Senorita, the chalices, por favor.
只有上帝才能賦予人永生
Only God can grant eternal life,
而不是這邪惡的泉水
not this pagan water.
士兵們  毀掉這褻瀆神聖的寺廟
Men, destroy this profane temple!
不老泉
The Fountain!
你這個蠢貨
You are a fool.
你在這追尋的東西  只有信仰才能提供
You seek in this place what only faith can provide.
信仰?  確實有照亮世界的光明
Faith? In faith, there is light enough to see
但也有吞噬萬物的黑暗
but darkness enough to blind.
這是在搞什麼鬼
What devilry is this?
-為了黑珍珠號  -你做了什麼
- For the Pearl. - What have you done?
安琪莉卡  別碰  有毒
Angelica! Don't! It's poison!
不用一點惡毒的伎倆
I'm not such the fool to take on Blackbeard
就想對付黑鬍子  我還沒這麼天真
without a little venomous advantage.
傑克
Jack!
黑鬍子的船和船員歸我所有
I claim Blackbeard's ship and crew,
還有這把劍  以此補償我失去的右腿
and this sword, payment for my missing limb!
抓緊  用力拉
Hang on! Pull!
別浪費我的眼淚
Do not waste my tear.
喝了這個  這杯埵陴散\
Drink this. This one has the tear.
-你得喝另一杯  -不
- You must drink the other. - No!
你們只有一個能活  另一個必須犧牲
I cannot save you both. One of you must sacrifice.
喝了它  父親  拯救你的靈魂
You take it, Father, for your soul.
提奇船長  她快死了  你得救你的女兒
Captain Teach, she's dying. You must save your daughter.
這一杯是奪走生命的嗎
This one takes life?
這一杯有眼淚能賦予生命
This one has the tear and gives life?
對  快喝
Aye, hurry!
安琪莉卡  救我  孩子
Angelica... Save me, my child.
不
No.
我愛你  父親
I love you, Father.
等等
Wait a minute.
事實上  好像弄反了
In fact, it might have been the other way around.
這一杯有眼淚  那一杯沒有
This cup had the tear, that one had the other bit.
騙子
Trickster!
-惡魔  -父親
- Devil! - Father!
你這混蛋  你怎麼敢
You bastard! How could you?
你父親救了你
Your father saved you.
或許他的靈魂現在得到了救贖
Perhaps his soul is now redeemed, eh?
你受傷了
You are hurt.
只是身體受傷
In body only.
我的心靈很平靜...因為你
My mind is at peace... because of you.
-我  -對
- Me? - Yes.
我曾迷失了自己
I was lost.
那狂風大浪
The wind, the tides...
應該能改變一個人的信仰
...they ought to renew a man's faith.
但對我而言  只有你能
But for me, only you.
菲利普  我可以救你
Philip, I can save you.
你只需開口請求我
You need only ask.
-我只求你一件事  -什麼
- I seek but one thing. - What is that?
寬恕
Forgiveness.
如果不是我  你就不會被抓
If not for me, you would never have been captured.
開口吧
Ask.
寬恕我
Forgive me?
我恨你
I hate you.
恨那個救了你的人嗎
The bloke who saved your life?
我的生命是從我父親那偷來的
The years I possess, stolen from my own father!
我只是幫黑鬍子盡了父親的責任
I only helped Blackbeard do what any father should have done.
你個冷血自大的混蛋
You are cruel and ignorant.
一把手槍  一枚子彈
One pistol, one shot.
好讓我在餓死前飲彈自盡嗎
To kill myself before I starve?
我可不信你會這麼做  寶貝
There's no trusting you, love.
再說了  這堬謚成茤嘛W繁
Besides, this is a well-traveled trade route.
你可以向它們發送求救信號
You can signal a passing ship.
或者像俗語說的那樣啃啃子彈
Or you can just bite the proverbial bullet, as it were.
喻指咬緊牙關  忍受苦難的現實
我怎麼才能弄開這些繩子
And how will I get free of these bonds?
半小時前你就掙開了
You broke free of your bonds half an hour ago,
等待襲擊的最佳時刻
waiting for the precise moment to pounce.
承認吧  傑克
Admit it, Jack.
-你還愛著我  -如果你有個妹妹和一條狗
- You still love me. - If you had a sister and a dog,
我會選擇狗
I'd choose the dog.
寶藏  有個裝滿珠寶的箱子
Treasure! There is a chest with jewels!
擁有征服風浪力量的珠寶
Jewels with the power to rule the wind and tide!
-你編的吧  -等等
- You're making that up! - Wait...
我有身孕了  你的
I am with child. Yours.
我不記得我們有過...
I don't recall that we ever had...
-你當時醉了  -我從沒醉到那種程度
- You were drunk! - I've actually never been that drunk.
等等
Wait!
我有件事要告訴你
There is something I want to say to you.
我們第一次相見時我就想說了
Something I wanted to say from the moment we first met.
那就說吧
Go on, then.
我愛你
I love you.
我也是
As do I.
以前愛  今後也愛
Always have. Always will.
我得走了
I gotta go.
傑克
Jack!
這事沒完
This is not over!
傑克
Jack!
沒打中
Missed!
復仇號是我的了[同時意為復了仇]
The Revenge is mine.
先生
Sir...
我們在甲板下發現了這個
We found this below decks.
全員  開往上風向
All hands! Ply to windward!
動起來  你們這群蟑螂
Get cracking, ye blooming cockroaches!
國王是對我不錯
The Crown served me well.
但如今  大海藍天諸神在上
But now, by the gods of sea and sky...
向托爾圖加島開進吧
...make way for Tortuga!
吉布斯  你這骯髒糊塗的老東西居然成功了
Gibbs, you filthy, besotted shellback, you made it!
是的
Aye!
我相信在這次的聯盟中
And I trust we managed a profit
-我們有所獲利  -請大飽眼福吧
- from our joint enterprise? - Feast your eyes.
指南針直接領我找到了它
The compass led me straight and true.
你怎麼對付黑鬍子船上的看守
What of Blackbeard's men guarding the ship?
我用了在新幾內亞大獲成功的那個辦法
I employed the selfsame maneuver we perfected in New Guinea.
如果留下一整只艦隊不拿就太可惜了
Seemed a shame to leave an entire fleet behind.
確實可惜
Shame indeed.
我恨那隻猴子
I hate that monkey.
黑珍珠號要怎麼弄出來
So, the Pearl... Any idea how to get her out?
我們需要一把弩  一個沙漏  三隻山羊
We shall need a crossbow, an hourglass, three goats.
我們中的一個
One of us must learn to play
得學會吹小號  另一個得這樣
the trumpet whilst the other one goes like this...
-我認識個人有山羊  -很好  那我可以這樣
- I know a man with a goat. - Good. I can go like this.
傑克  我想問問
Jack, I have to ask...
你有了聖盃  泉水還有眼淚
You had the chalices, the water, the tear...
你大概能長命百歲
You could have lived maybe forever.
不老泉會考驗你  吉布斯
The Fountain does test you, Gibbs.
但最好還是別知道何時是生命的盡頭
But better to not know which moment may be your last.
在生命中的每個瞬間
Every morsel of your entire being
都能感受到生命本身無限的奧秘
alive to the infinite mystery of it all.
再說  誰說我不會長命百歲
And who's to say I won't live forever, eh?
不老泉的發現者
Discoverer of the Fountain of Youth.
這事我說不了算  吉布斯
I have no say in it, Gibbs.
我注定是個海盜
It's a pirate's life for me.
懂了嗎
Savvy?